Bryan Ehlinger Collection of Posters ARC.0118
Library and Archives
Bryan Ehlinger Collection of Posters
1978-1989, 1994, undated
ARC.0118
Library and Archives
4.0 Linear feet (1 shared flat file drawer)
The Bryan Ehlinger Collection of Posters consists of promotional posters used by record companies for advertising and in-store displays from 1978 to 1989 and 1994. Performers include David Bowie, Genesis, Jefferson Starship, Moody Blues, The Scorpions, and Trooper. The Collection provides a glimpse into how record companies promoted their artists and the records they released during the late 1970s and 1980s. Seen in a broader context, the Collection provides insight to the images and styles used to promote rock and roll music.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Patrons must sign the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibility and Privacy Rights statement on the Researcher Registration form before using this collection. Consult the Library and Archives in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
Scope and Contents
The Bryan Ehlinger Collection of Posters is arranged alphabetically.
Biographical Note
Bryan Elhinger is currently the Nursing Home Administrator of Oneida Healthcare Center's Extended Care Facility in Oneida, New York, where he has worked in various capacities since 1985. Ehlinger received a bachelor's degree in Healthcare Management from State University of New York Insititute of Technology at Utica / Rome in 2002.
Sources
"Bryan Ehlinger." Oneida Healthcare Center: Exceptional Care...Always. Last modified 2011. Accessed June 29, 2011. http://www.oneidahealthcare.org/news/index.cfm?action=view&newsitem_id=98.
Custodial History note
The Bryan Ehlinger Collection of Posters was received by the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, Inc. from Bryan Ehlinger on July 7, 2005.
Bowie, David; Ehlinger, Bryan; Genesis (Musical group); Scorpions (Musical group); Posters; Rock music--Posters
- Asia: Alpha, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 1)
  Museum Accession Number
  A2005.36.17
- Bad Company: Rough Diamonds and back catalog, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 2)
- Big Country: The Crossing, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 1)
  A2005.36.34
- Black Crowes: Amorica, 1994 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 2)
  A2005.36.35
- Bow Wow Wow: The Last of the Mohicans, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 3)
  A2005.36.28
- Bowie, David: Changes One and Changes Two, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 3)
  A2005.36.16
- Bowie, David: "China Girl", 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 4)
  A2005.36.44
- Bowie, David: "Let’s Dance" [Single], 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 5)
  A2005.36.50
- Bowie David: Musician Magazine - “The David Bowie Interview”, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 4)
  A2005.36.59
- Bowie, David: Original Soundtrack from the film Christina F., 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 5)
  A2005.36.7
- Bowie, David: "Tonight" [Single], 1984 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 6-7)
  A2005.36.19, A2005.36.53
- Collins, Phil: Face Value, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 6)
  A2005.36.32
- Concerts for the People of Kampuchea: Clash; Costello, Elvis & The Attractions; Dury, Ian & The Blockheads; McCartney, Paul & Wings; Pretenders; Queen; Rockestra; Rockpile; Specials; Who, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 7)
  A2005.36.22
- Crosby, Stills and Nash: Allies, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 8)
  A2005.36.13
- Def Leppard: Pyromania, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 9)
  A2005.36.21
- Dokken: Breakin’ the Chains, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 8)
  A2005.36.3
- Dolby, Thomas: Aliens Ate My Buick, 1988 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 9)
  Museum Accession NUmber
  A2005.36.31
- Doobie Brothers, 1980 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 10)
  A2005.36.10
- Ford, Lita Out For Blood, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 11)
  A2005.36.6
- Gabriel, Peter: Security, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 12)
  A2005.36.30
- Genesis on Atlantic Records and Tapes, circa 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 13)
  A2005.36.64
- Genesis on Atlantic Records, Cassettes, & Compact Discs, circa 1986 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 10)
  A2005.36.48
- Genesis: Abacab, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 14, Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 11)
  A2005.36.40, A2005.36.55
- Genesis: Genesis, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 15)
  A2005.36.54
- Genesis: Genesis and back catalog, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 16)
  A2005.36.61
- Genesis: Three Sides Live, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 17)
  A2005.36.65
- Head East: US 1, 1980 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 12)
  Museum Accession Numbers
  A2005.36.47
- Jefferson Starship: Freedom at Point Zero and back catalog, 1979 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 18)
  A2005.36.37
- Jefferson Starship: Modern Times, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 13)
  A2005.36.51
- Jon Butcher Axis, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 19)
  A2005.36.29
- Journey: Departure, 1980 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 14)
  A2005.36.49
- Kings X: Gretchen Goes to Nebraska, 1989 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 15)
  A2005.36.14
- Led Zeppelin: Coda, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 20)
  A2005.36.18
- Marillion: Script for a Jester’s Tear, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 21)
  A2005.36.63
- Moody Blues: Long Distance Voyager, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 22)
  A2005.36.24
- Moody Blues: Long Distance Voyager and back catalog (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 23)
  A2005.36.58
- Moore, Gary on Mirage Records & Cassettes, undated (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 24)
  A2005.36.12
- Motley Crue: Shout at the Devil, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 25)
  A2005.36.15
- Nazareth: It's Naz, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 16-18)
  A2005.36.8, A2005.36.38, A2005.36.39
- Plant, Robert: The Principles of Moments, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 26)
  A2005.36.57
- Police: Ghost in the Machine, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 19)
  A2005.36.36
- Prism: Small Change, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 27)
  A2005.36.11
- Rainbow: Straight Between the Eyes, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 28)
  A2005.36.2
- Ripperton, Minnie: The Best of Minnie Ripperton, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 29)
  A2005.36.25
- Rolling Stones: Undercover, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 30)
  A2005.36.42
- Roxy Music: Avalon, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 31)
  A2005.36.60
- Rush: Exit Stage Left, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 32)
  A2005.36.4
- Rutherford, Mike: Acting Very Strange, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 33)
  A2005.36.62
- Scorpions: Blackout, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 20)
  A2005.36.26
- Scorpions: Blackout and back catalog, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 21)
  A2005.36.46
- Scorpions: Love at First Sting and back catalog, 1984 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 22)
  A2005.36.5
- Spring Fling 1985: McGuinn, Roger; Sebastian, John; Hall, John, 1985 April 26 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 34)
  A2005.36.20
- Springsteen, Bruce and the E Street Band: Live, 1975-1985, 1986 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 23)
  A2005.36.52
- Stray Cats: "Sexy and 17"; "Lucky Charm"; "Cruisin'"; "Lookin' Better Every Beer", 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 24)
  A2005.36.45
- Thorpe, Billy: Children of the Sun, 1979 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 25)
  A2005.36.9
- Triumph: Allied Forces and back catalog, 1981 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 26)
  A2005.36.41
- Trooper: Money Talks, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 35)
  A2005.36.23
- Trooper: Thick as Thieves, 1978 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 27)
  A2005.36.43
- Uriah Heep: Head First, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 28)
  A2005.36.33
- Who: It’s Hard, 1982 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-2, Object 29)
  A2005.36.27
- ZZ Top: Eliminator, 1983 (Drawer-folder FF.1.7-1, Object 36)
  A2005.36.56